Guide to the Barbara L. Kevles Collection of Computer Technology M1588
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Barbara L. Kevles collection of computer technology
1993-2006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kevles, Barbara L.
M1588
2.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Collection of operating manuals, software, and related material, assembled by journalist Barbara Kevles.
Scope and Contents
Journalist, author, and archivist Barbara Kevles used the same personal computer from 1993 through 2006. During those fourteen years, she added only a few essential programs such as financial and security software because of the restrictions placed by the PC’s miniscule 170 megabyte hard drive. Out of necessity, she kept her operating system, monitor, and printer manuals as well as allied materials to operate her computer and fix periodic malfunctions as the radically changing computer world replaced her platform, programs and eliminated support services. She recorded her user problems with an IBM compatible computer and peripheries in detail in 12 notebooks.
As a result, The Barbara L. Kevles Collection of Computer Technology is comprised of over a hundred published and unpublished documents, software, and miscellaneous equipment that create a marker from which to measure the rapid evolution of home computer technology starting in the 1990s through today.
Software and documentation has been placed into boxes without folders. Post-it Notes have been left intact. Photocopies and author's notes have been re-housed in acid-free folders, maintaining original titles. For the most detailed listing, please refer to the "The Catalogue of the Barbara L. Kevles Collection of Computer Technology" prepared by Kevles found in Box 1, Folder 1.
The collection includes guides, manuals, installation software, historic Norton newsletters, hand-written notebooks, correspondence, demonstration trial software-- all for precedent-setting operating systems, early program applications, analog monitors, seminal printers, modems, motherboards, internet service providers, financial software, and antivirus programs.
Related Materials
Stanford Special Collections also holds the Barbara L. Kevles Collection on Gordon Parks (M1409): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/5659444
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Software is available for visual review only.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Barbara L. Kevles, 2007. Accession 2007-229.
Operating systems (Computers); Computer industry -- United States -- History; Kevles, Barbara L.
- Catalogue of the Barbara L. Kevles Collection of Computer Technology of the 1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Dallas Morning News clippings (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Microsoft Office Suite (Box 1, Object 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Microsoft Office Standard. Upgrade WIN/OFF Version 4.2 021-051-425 Getting Started discs #1-25, 5 packets of 5 1.44 MB floppy discs Windows Series Version 4.2 Set up instructions Except #25 - Powerpoint Viewer
- Getting Started Manual (101 pages) (Box 1, Object 4)
- Microsoft Office Standard Supplemental Offers (2 pages) (Box 1, Object 5)
- Microsoft License Agreement (Box 1, Object 6)
- Access Advertisement (Box 1, Object 7)
- User's Guide Microsoft Powerpoint (302 pages) (Box 1, Object 8)
- Important Information about your Microsoft Mail Workstation License (3 pages) (Box 1, Object 9)
- User's Guide Microsoft Query (168 pages) (Box 1, Object 10)
- Visual Basic User's Guide Microsoft Excel (344 pages) (Box 1, Object 11)
- User's Guide Microsoft Excel (786 pages) (Box 1, Object 12)
- Cardboard strips Wordperfect 5.1 showing Control, Shift, Alt shortcuts for F Function keys (2) (Box 1, Object 13)
- Cardboard strips Microsoft Word 5.0 showing Control, Shift, Alt shortcuts for F Function keys (2) (Box 1, Object 14)
- Foldout quick reference card carbon copy: mail for MS-DOS (6 pages) (Box 1, Object 15)
- Lotus 1-2-3 1.0 Qwik Reference Guide (Box 1, Object 16)
- Microsoft Word 2.0 Qwik Reference Guides (2) (Box 1, Object 17)
- MS-Word 5.5 Guide (Box 1, Object 18)
- Wordperfect 5.1 Quick Reference Guides (2) (Box 1, Object 19)
- Excel 4.0 Qwick Reference Guides (2) (Box 1, Object 20)
- Microsoft Excel 5.0 Qwick Reference Guide (Box 1, Object 21)
- Microsoft Word 5.0 Reference Guide (Box 1, Object 22)
- Wordperfect 5.1 Reference Guide (Box 1, Object 23)
- Microsoft Excel 3.0 Reference Guide (Box 1, Object 24)
- Microsoft Word 2.0 Reference Guide (Box 1, Object 25)
- Discover the World Wide Web with your Sportster (206 pages) (Box 1, Object 26)
- Quick Start Here Installation and Troubleshooting Sportster Modem (59 pages) (Box 1, Object 27)
- Sportster Quicklink II Fax Software Installation Guide (Box 1, Object 28)
- Quicklink II Fax and Telecommunications Windows and DOS (164 pages) (Box 1, Object 29)
- Quicklink II Fax and Telecommunications disc 1.44 MB (Box 1, Object 30)
- Wordperfect 5.1 Made Easy by Mella Mincberg (1071 pages) (Box 2, Object 1)
- Mindspring Internet Connection Kit, version 3.08 trial CD. (Box 2, Object 2)
- America Online Installation disc (Box 2, Object 3)
- Norton Antivirus 3.0 (Box 2, Object 4)
  in box: 1.44 MB floppy discs (3) version 3.0 (installation discs), 1.44 MB floppy discs, version 3.0 2/96 (3), 1.44 MB floppy discs Virus Definitions, Summer, 1997 (2), 1.44 MB floppy discs Virus Definitions, Fall, 1997 (2),, User's Guide Symantec Norton Antivirus 3.0
- Hewlett Packard recycling information (Box 2, Object 5)
- CPA Vision (Compact Disc) (Box 2, Object 6)
- Compuserve Gold 250 hours (Compact Disc) (Box 2, Object 7)
- Symantec Norton Antivirus 4.0 (Box 2, Object 8)
- 1.44 MB virus definitions for Norton Antivirus, Winter, 1997 (3) (Box 2, Object 9)
- America Online 7.0 1025 hours free trial (Compact Disc) (Box 2, Object 10)
- American Online 7.0 1000 hours free trial (Compact Disc) (Box 2, Object 11)
- Barcode Scanner (Box 2, Object 12)
- Norton Antivirus Emergency Boot disc (Box 2, Object 13)
- Symantec: Installing new virus definitions: guide (8 pages) (Box 2, Object 14)
- 1.44 MB virus definitions Norton Antivirus, Spring, 1998 (4) (Box 2, Object 15)
- Symantec: Installing new virus definitions: guide (9 pages) (Box 2, Object 16)
- Symantec Ad for Earthlink (Box 2, Object 17)
- Symantec business reply by mail (Box 2, Object 18)
- Microsoft Works 2.0 (Box 3, Object 1)
  1.44 MB discs for setup, help, clip art (5), 1.44 MB program discs (2), 5 1/4" program discs (4)
- Getting Started Microsoft Works 46 pages (Box 3, Object 2)
- Intuit Advertisement (Box 3, Object 3)
- Prodigy 1 month free trial (Box 3, Object 4)
- UM 486V A10 User's Manual for motherboard (Box 3, Object 5)
- US 3486 User's Manual for motherboard (Box 3, Object 6)
- Truecolor Video Board Compudyne (manual) (Box 3, Object 7)
- MIO - 400KF Rev. F All-In-One Input/Output User's Manual (Box 3, Object 8)
- Compudyne KD - 1450T Color Monitor Operation and Installation Guide (14 pages) (Box 3, Object 9)
- Compudyne Microsoft MS-DOS 5.0 5 1/4 "floppy discs, with License Agreement (2) (Box 3, Object 10)
- Video Drivers VC 500 Utility diskette Version 1.43, 1.44 MB (2) (Box 3, Object 11)
- Compudyne True Color Utility/Driver (5 1/4" floppy disc) (Box 3, Object 12)
- Compudyne True Color Windows 3.0/3.1 (5 1/4" disc) (Box 3, Object 13)
- America Online Version 2.5 10 hours free (trial 1.44 MB disc) (Box 3, Object 14)
- Compudyne Microsoft MS-DOS 5.0 concise edition (170 pages) (Box 3, Object 15)
- Juno: free internet trial (email service, 1.44 MB disc) (Box 3, Object 16)
- Ad: Imation Super (120 MB disc) (Box 3, Object 17)
- Quicken 2001 deluxe (Compact Disc) (Box 3, Object 18)
- America Online 9.0 1045 hours free (trial Compact Disc) (Box 3, Object 19)
- America Online 9.0 1099 hours free (trial Compact Disc) (Box 3, Object 20)
- America Online 6.0 700 hours free (trial Compact Disc) (Box 3, Object 21)
- America Online 7.0 1000 hours free (trial Compact Disc; 2) (Box 3, Object 22)
- Verizon Online DLS demonstration discs (2) (Box 3, Object 23)
- American Online 6.0 700 hours free (trial Compact Disc; 7) (Box 3, Object 24)
- Microsoft Windows Operation System Version 3.1 1.44 MB installation discs. (Box 3, Object 25)
  Disc#7 labeled Windows Driver (7)
- 1.44 MB disc Copy of Artisoft (program to connect 2 computers) 6 executable program files (Box 3, Object 26)
- 1.44 MB disc Copy of Prodigy 15 program files (Box 3, Object 27)
- 1.44 MB disc Copy of Check It 15 program files (Box 3, Object 28)
  Copy of DA 5 7 program files
- 1.44 MB disc Copy of DA 5 6 program files (Box 3, Object 29)
  Copy of Mouse 15 program files, Copy of Norton 3 program files including one from 1/1/1980, Copy of Winpak 5 program files
- 1.44 MB disc from Computerprep with training for Microsoft Word for Windows Version 6.0 Module 1 Rev1.1 (Box 3, Object 30)
- 1.44 MB disc Microsoft Word Version 6.0 Lessons 22 items (Box 3, Object 31)
- HP3P form, tests, fonts, cleaning paper (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Wordperfect 6 Windows (299 pages) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Compudyne Microsoft Windows 3.1: concise edition (1997 pages) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Computerprep, Inc.: instructions to merge documents, create/use tables (fax pp2-30) 10/2/95 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Norton form letters to customers signed Peter Norton (4) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Norton to customers reporting the number and increased frequency of new viruses discovered daily and the switch from a quarterly to a monthly release of new antivirus definitions, 14" Ultra VGA Color Monitor User's Manual (18 pages, Xeroxed; Signed by Korean Quality Control Manager), Letter from Intuit signed Intuit management: Scott Cook, et al., Virus, before and after
- Clippings re: Computers, Summer and Fall, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Word 6.0 for Windows The Visual Quick Reference (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Norton Antivirus for Windows 3.X/Dos User’s Guide (4) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Handwritten notes by Kevles (Box 4, Folder 9)
  "Norton Antivirus installation and scans of three 1.44 MB discs with negative results."
- Symantec AntiVirus News Update (3) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Hewlett Packard LaserJet IIIP Printer User's Quick Reference Guide (8 pages) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Hewlett Packard LaserJet IIIP Printer Getting Started Guide (32 pages, first edition) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Hewlett Packard LaserJet IIIP Printer User’s Manual (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Hewlett Packard LaserJet II/IIID/IIIP Printer Software Application Notes (Chapters 1-5) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Handwritten Notebooks by Kevles (11 pages) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  topics include: program registration; addition of icon to toolbar; Norton reinstallation and virus scan; retrieval of lost c drive financial data from a drive; printer noises; blurred print, repairs, and replacement; deletion of hidden, but unnecessary files from c drive for net gain of nearly 9 million bites; information on printer, monitor, font drivers; directions to copy, delete directories, files, program icons, discs; use of fax modem; installation of new motherboard; method to retrieve hidden files in DOS; complete list of first computer equipment bought 1/13/93; various monitor problems and replacement; DOS code for time; 1995 installation MS Office (76 MG), Quicken; listed size of each program on computer; power surge repercussion.
- TurboTax Head Start version and Quicken 4 (Box 5, Object 2)
  Original box for Quicken Version 4 and Turbo Tax head Start Version 94.0 with Quicken requirements of minimum computer speed, version of Windows, memory capacity, hard drive space, and monitor level; Mail-in card for final version of Turbo Tax containing IRS forms for filing; Ads for Turbo Tax (6 pages), for Quicken Online (4 pages), for Intuit checks, Quicken electronic bill payment (10 pages), Quicken Visa card (4 pages), mailer for Quicken 4 Windows 5 1/4" discs; Turbo Tax for Windows Personal/1040 Head Start Tax Year 1994 Version 94.0 1.44 MB discs (4)
- Xerox TabWorks Brochure (1.44 MB trial demonstration disc) (Box 5, Object 3)